Ruben Alcazar Alvarez

Full Stack Developer

+52 33 34880050 Telephone Email alkazar.r@gmail.com Address Zapopan, Mexico.



Summary

Full Stack Developer with strong background in Node.js, React, PostgreSQL and Mongo, i have worked in startups for the last three years which involves bitcoin casinos and a Silicon Valley based social network startup (Wiselike.com). Worked both remotely and personally.

Strong experience in:

Server: Node.js, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Koa, Express.

Client: Javascript, HTML, CSS, SASS, React.js, Flux, Baobab.js, Webpack.

I love to work with new and experienced people, i'm an startups fan and love to build cool stuff, open agriculture, and knowing new

Experience

2015 - 2016 Full Stack Developer, Wiselike.com

- Worked in almost all parts of the site, from databases and server to LESS client side.
- Used ES6 and React.js with server side rendering.
- Worked on client side render optimization.
- Helped in the design of a redis based tor proxy provider.
- Helped in open source scrapping projects.

Bitcoin casino startup venture, Moneypot.com 2013 - 2015

- Developed a bitcoin casino from the ground with a partner.
- Learned a lot about security.

Web developer, AgaveLab	2013 - 2014
-------------------------	-------------

- Used Node.js and React.js for diverse projects.
- Reconstructed Avisora.mx codebase.

Sexshop startup venture, SomosPuntoG 2013 - 2013

- Started a Mexican online sexshop with some parters.
- Designed and Constructed a condoms electronic vending machine.

Web developer, NetMarketingWeb 2012 - 2013

- Used frameworkless OOP PHP, MySQL, CSS, HTML, Javascript.
- Integrated payment services.

Work on the development of a CRM.

DirecTV technical support, Hispanic Teleservices. 2011 - 2011

Electronic circuits designer, Infra-Tecno 2009 - 2011

Education

- Developed a circuit for automating gas heaters and humidity in poultry using PIC microcontroller programmed in C and analog circuits.
- Worked on field implementation of the system.

Technical Skills

NodeJS MongoDB PostgreSQL	Informatics Technologist, Centro de Enseñanza Técnica Industrial (CETI) Guadalajara, Mexico	2005 - 2009
Koa Express	Electronics Engineering, ITESO (50%) Guadalajara, Mexico	2009 - 2012
ES6	Gudulujulu, Mexico	

Javascript HTML CSS

SASS ReactJS

BaobabJS

Flux

Used before: PHP, C, C++, Verilog, VHDL, assembler, Java, Processing, CoffeeScript, ActionScript, JQuery, Knockout.js, backbone.js, PhoneGap

Interests

Travel, movies, cars, reading, tech, startups, running, cycling, memory improvement, open agriculture...

References

David Oliveros, Wiselike CTO

+52 81 15364774 | david@careerdean.com

Alberto Ortiz Ascencio, Unosquare Mx Digital Marketing +52 33 39548781 | albint3r@gmail.com